Don't listen to yourself. Start talking
to yourself. Too many times during a
match when we're in that chair, we're
starting to feel sorry for ourselves. We
start to focus on the bad roles, the
negatives. This is a sign that you're on
the crossroads. Keep listening and you
can spiral out of control very easily
and very fast. Or you can start talking
to yourself in a constructive, helpful
way. Start with a couple of nice deep
breaths to supply your brain with enough
quality oxygen. And then have a couple
of words ready written down or in your
mind that you can look at or repeat in
your mind. No more than three words. For
example, soft, ready, composed, or
focus, trust, attack, or how about
respect, humble, focus, you name it.
Choose three words that have a strong
meaning for you. Start talking to
yourself today and stop listening. Go
for it. Good luck.